https://www.walthers.com/privacy-policy-cookie-restriction-mode

Shop All Departments
TrainsFreight CarsAuto RackBoxcarCabooseCircusCoil CarContainerDisplays and AssortmentsFlatcarGondolaHolidayHopperIntermodalLoggingMiningOre CarReeferSetSpecial Decoration/ CommemorativeSteel Mill CarStock CarTank CarTrack CleaningWork CarLocomotives/TractionDieselDisplays and AssortmentsElectricOtherRail CarSpecial Decoration/ CommemorativeSteamTurbinePassengerCircusDisplays and AssortmentsEuropean/ Non-North AmericanExcursionExpressHolidayHeavyweightSpecial Decoration/ CommemorativeSteam Generator CarStreamlinedRailcar/ Traction TrailerWoodTrain SetsCircusCircus - Train OnlyCombination Freight & Passenger Set CompleteCombination Freight & Passenger - Trains OnlyDisplays and AssortmentsFreight Set CompleteFreight - Train OnlyHolidayHoliday - Train OnlyPassenger Set CompletePassenger - Train OnlySpecial Decoration/ CommemorativeSpecial Decoration - Train OnlyLayoutFiguresAccessoryAnimalDisplays and AssortmentsPeopleMilitaryAccessoryAircraftArmored VehicleArtilleryAutomobileBoatBusConstructionMotorcycle/ BicycleDecalEmergencyFigureRailroadSetStructureTankTrailerTruckVanWagonSceneryBackground SceneDisplays and AssortmentsGround CoverHolidayLayouts Bases/ Forms, Dioramas & AccessoriesMolding Materials (Plaster etc.)PlantRoads/ Streets/ HighwaysRocks & MountainsScenery DetailsSetScenic StructureTreesWater & AccessoriesSignals, Detection Units & SignsDetection Units & AccessoriesDisplays and AssortmentsSignSignalStructuresAssortmentBridges & ViaductsBusiness/ Commercial BuildingCableway/ Funicular RailwayCastleReligious/ Place of WorshipCraneDisplays and AssortmentsGarageHolidayHousingIndustrialModular Building ComponentsOutbuildingPlatforms/ Shelters/ RampsPublic/ MunicipalRailroadRecreation/ Sports/ EntertainmentRural StructureSmokestacks/ ChimneysStation/ Depot/ TerminalTanks & TowersWaterfrontWindmills/ Wind GeneratorsTrack and AccessoriesAccessoryBumper/ Wheel StopCatenary & AccessoriesDisplays and AssortmentsFlexible TrackHand Lay Track ProductsJoinerMarklin 3-Rail HO Track SystemNarrow GaugeRoadbed TrackRoadbedSectional TrackSetSpecial PurposeTrack DetailsTerminal Track/ Joiner/ Power FeedTurnoutSwitch Machine/ Turnout AccessoryTrack ToolCrossingVehiclesAircraftAutomobileBoatBusCircusConstructionCraneMotorcycle/ BicycleDisplays and AssortmentsEmergencyFarmForkliftHolidayLoggingMaintenanceOperatingRaceRailroadRecreational VehicleSetSpecial Decoration/ CommemorativeSUVTrailerTruckVanWagonReference BooksName TrainsSuper Chief - El CapitanLocomotivesHi-Level & Conventional CarsDeluxe Edition CarsAdd-on Santa Fe CarsCornerstone® Structure KitsLighting KitsTwin Cities HiawathaCity of Los AngelesC&O George WashingtonBroadway LimitedThe Capitol LimitedSan Francisco Chief Empire Builder1951 Super Chief Pere MarquetteAmfleet CarsMetroliner1956 El CapitanUP Cities20th Century LimitedMilwaukee RoadHiawathaSanta Fe 1954 El CapitanOn Sale TodayBargain DepotAll On SaleThe Warehouse SaleNew Product CenterJust AnnouncedAdvanced ReservationsNew ArrivalsPower and ControlsCommand ControlAccessoryDecoderSetLighting, Electrical, MotorsDisplays and AssortmentsElectricalLightingMotors & AccessoriesPower Supplies, Sound, Smoke SystemAccessoryCameraDisplays and AssortmentsPower Pack (Train Speed Controller)Power SupplySmokeSoundThrottle (All Types)AccessoriesCouplers and TrucksAccessoryCouplerTruck w/Attached Coupler (Talgo)TrucksWheelsDecalsAlphabet/ NumberCircusDisplays and AssortmentsFilmGraffitiHolidayDecal Making SuppliesBlank Decal PaperPinewood DerbyRailroadSetting SolutionSignSpecial Decoration/ CommemorativeStripesTexture OverlayVehicleSuper Detailing PartsDisplays and AssortmentsLocomotiveRepair PartRolling StockSetStructureVehicleScratch Building SuppliesDisplays and AssortmentsHardwareMetalOtherPlasticRoofing MaterialsWoodTools & FinishingAdhesives, Cleaners and LubricantsApplicatorCleanerDisplays and AssortmentsGlues, Tape & AdhesivesLubricantFillers & PuttiesSolderPaint and Paint SuppliesAirbrushes & AccessoriesDisplays and AssortmentsMilitary ColorOtherPainting SuppliesRailroadToolsDisplays and AssortmentsHand ToolPower ToolSetStorage & CarriersWork Stations & Lights, Cutting MatsRailroadianaBooks, Videos and RailroadianaAudioBookComputer RelatedDisplays and AssortmentsDVDMagazineMultimedia/ Book on CD/DVDRailroadianaStorage/ Display CaseVideoRacing and ToysRoad RacingAccessoryCarDisplays and AssortmentsSetToysCarDisplays and AssortmentsGliderJack-in-the-BoxMusic BoxNoodleOther ToyOther Vehicles & AccessoriesPlay Set (Non-Vehicle)TopTrains & Accessories (Non-Scale Models)
Walthers Brands
Walthers Controls (942)
Walthers Cornerstone (933)
Walthers SceneMaster (949)
Walthers Tools & Screws (947)
WalthersMainline (910)
WalthersN (929)
WalthersProto (920)
WalthersTrack (948)
WalthersTrainline (931)
Manufacturer List
New Products
On Sale
Resources
Hobbyist Help
Getting Started in the Hobby
Full Steam Ahead
Build My Wishlist
Overview
Walthers (“We”, "Us”, or “Our”) recognize the need for protection and management of your personal information. We have therefore adopted this Privacy Statement to assist you in understanding what information We collect and how that information is used and shared. This Privacy Statement applies to the information We collect when you access any Walthers website, when you purchase or use a Walthers product, or when you provide any non-public information to us.
Before you access any Walthers website, such as http://www.walthers.com, purchase or use Walthers products or services, or provide any non- public information to Us, you should review this Privacy Statement to understand Our information collection and use practices.
Information We Collect
We collect certain categories of information about you and the device that you are using, particularly when you visit Our websites but also when you use or purchase Our products or when you provide us information to deliver you newsletters and other communications. In particular:
Contact Information: Contact information is information or data that can be used to identify or contact a specific individual. For example, when you access Our websites, We ask you to provide certain contact information when you create an account, such as your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, previous order information, user IDs, passwords, and contact preferences. If you do not wish to provide the information requested, you may not be able to proceed with the activity or receive the benefit for which the personal information is being requested.
Payment Information: If you purchase a product or service from Walthers, you will need to provide us with payment information. This may include billing and other transaction information, credit card number, or other financial information that we can use to ensure proper payment for the products or services you are purchasing.
Device Information: We gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you.
Tracking and Location Information.
We may collect and/or track certain information that is derived from the use of Our products such as usage patterns, web site page views and traffic patterns. We may use this tracking and location information for statistical purposes to improve Our products and services and to help users manage their environment and infrastructure more efficiently.
3RD Party Applications:  We may collect your contact information via mobile apps or other online and offline systems via 3rd party applications. Our service providers track and collect app usage data and we will retain your app credentials in order to administer processes within the app. We shall make reasonable efforts to insure that all 3rd party applications protect information to the extent required by applicable law.
Other Personal Information:
We may collect data you voluntarily provide regarding your interests, demographics, communication preferences via surveys administered via phone, email, online, or at events. This data is requested in the interest of providing products, services, and communications that are relevant to you.
Cookies and Similar Technologies
“Cookies” are small text files that are placed on your computer, smartphone or other device when you visit a website. Walthers works with third party service providers and partners (including marketing partners, customer service providers, and others) to use cookies, beacons, and similar technology for a number of purposes. For example, these technologies are used in:
Analyzing site usage trends;
Administering the site;
Tracking users’ movements around the site;
Gathering demographic information about Our user base as a whole;
Saving your shopping cart;
Identifying users to remember users’ settings;
For authentication and to help you shop on Our site.
Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. If you reject cookies, you may still use Our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of Our site may be limited.
How We Use the Information We Collect
We use the information We collect to provide and enhance Our products and services, to operate Our business (e.g. billing and other accounting purposes; establishing accounts and contacting you regarding important information about your account, including notices and updates), for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes (including providing your contact information to third parties with whom Walthers has a relationship), for statistical analysis, for product development, to contact you regarding Our products and services, to monitor and maintain Our network, and to address issues that may arise concerning claims of abuse or inappropriate activity. For example, We may use the information We collect for the following purposes:
Displaying personalized content and advertising;
Information security and IT management;
Informing you of other products or services offered by Us;
Sending you relevant survey invitations;
Providing you with additional materials regarding Our products and services or to connect you with a Walthers representative;
Responding directly to your questions, comments or requests for support;
Analyzing site usage to improve and customize Our web sites, products, and service offerings;
Improving Our marketing and promotional efforts; and
Enforcing Our agreements with you.
Some of the information We collect allows Us to differentiate users on Our network, and in some cases, We act as a pass-through for certain pieces of information to obtain authentication for Internet access. If Our use of your data is governed by the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), you should know that we rely on the following legal grounds to process your personal information:
Performance of a contract – To the extent you have purchased a product or service from Walthers, we may need to collect and use your personal information to perform the services which you have purchased. For example, we may use your personal information to respond to requests you make via Our website and provide you with such services.
Compliance with law – In certain circumstances we may be required to process your data to comply with legal obligations to which Walthers is subject.
Consent – Some of the personal information We collect is provided by you voluntarily, for example when you sign up to join a mailing list or register for an event, and is therefore collected and used with your permission. To withdraw your consent to such use, you can contact us at privacy@walthers.com.
Legitimate interests – We may use your personal information for Our legitimate interests, such as to improve Our products and services and the content on Walthers websites. We may also use your contact information to keep you and others who have provided us with their contact information up-to-date on recent product and service developments. It you wish us to stop using your contact information in this manner, you can contact us at privacy@walthers.com.
How We Share Information We May Receive
We may from time to time disclose personal data to Our affiliates, and partners for the purpose of assisting Us in providing products or services, handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support, hosting websites, customer billing, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of Our services. Those companies will be permitted to obtain only the information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose.
We may disclose any information We collect from you if We believe such action is necessary to: (a) comply with any law, judicial proceeding, government request, court order, legal process, rule or regulation or any process served on Us; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Walthers (including the enforcement of Our agreements and investigation of potential violations thereof); (c) protect your safety or the safety of others; (d) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or (e) act in urgent circumstances or emergencies. If We are acquired by or merged with a third party, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on Our website of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information. We reserve the right to transfer the personal information We have collected as part of that transaction or proposed transaction, provided that such third party agrees to maintain procedures no less protective than those found in Our Privacy Statement.
Accessing And Changing Your Personal Information
Depending on the relevant jurisdiction, you may have certain rights granted to you by law with respect to the personal information Walthers and others have collected about you. For example, if the GDPR applies to the data We have collected about you, you have the right to access and correct data We have about you, to object to the processing of data, and to request that any information we have about you be erased.
You may request to exercise these rights by managing your account through Our website or by emailing Our data privacy team at privacy@walthers.com. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe, but no later than one month after you submit the request. . If your data is protected under the CCPA, you may make a personal information request twice in a twelve month period. We will respond to your request within 45 days of receiving the request.
To protect your privacy and security, we may require steps to verify your identity, such as a password and user ID, before granting access to your data.
If you wish to submit a personal data request, access or modify your information that you have voluntarily submitted or request that we not use such information for a particular purpose, such as receiving communications from Walthers, please contact us at:
5601 W. Florist Ave.
Milwaukee, WI 53218 email privacy@walthers.com
Please refer to special instructions for CCPA privacy requests below.
Third Party Sites and Services
Related offerings with links from Walthers websites have their own privacy policies that can be viewed by clicking on the corresponding links within each respective website. All Walthers partners are required to participate in industry privacy initiatives as required by law, and to take a responsible attitude towards consumer privacy.
We recommend and encourage that you always review the privacy policies of those third parties before you provide any personal information or complete any transaction with such parties.
Our web site also includes social media features, such as buttons for Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, and Instagram as well as widgets and interactive mini-programs that run on Our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on Our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on Our web site, therefore your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy statement of those third parties.
Collection and Use of Children's Personal Information
Other than the use of cookies via its consumer facing websites, Walthers does not knowingly collect or use personal information from children under the age of 13, or equivalent minimum age in the respective jurisdiction. If Walthers learns that we have personal information on a child under the age of 13, or equivalent minimum age depending on jurisdiction, we will take steps to delete that information from Our systems. If you are a parent or guardian and have concern that data has been provided by your child, please contact us at privacy@walthers.com so we may investigate and delete this data.
Security
Walthers takes information security seriously and uses reasonable measures to protect your information from unauthorized access. When you place orders on Our websites, all of your order information, including your credit card number and delivery address, is transmitted through the Internet using Transport Layer Security (TLS) technology. TLS technology causes your browser to encrypt your order information before transmitting it to Our secure server. We use a variety of security technologies depending on the situation to help protect your information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure, such as physical access controls, TLS, Internet firewalls, and network monitoring. However, no security system is 100% secure, and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of your information or assume liability for improper access to it. If you use a password to help protect your information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential, change the password frequently and use a strong password. We strongly recommend that you do not share this password with anyone and that you do not use your Walthers password on any other site or for any other purpose.
California Residents
California law provides California customers the right to request from Walthers certain details about how certain types of their information are shared with third parties, and in some cases, affiliates, for those third parties’ and affiliates own direct marketing purposes. To see those rights, click here. If you would like to request this information, please email your request to privacy@walthers.com or mail a letter to Attn: Walthers Privacy Administrator 5601 W. Florist Ave. Milwaukee, WI 53218
Requests must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the email subject line or in the first line of the description on your mailed letter. The request must include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code in the request. If you would like to provide your email address, please do so. Please note that Walthers is not required to respond to requests made by means other than through the provided email address or mail address.
Data Retention
We will retain your Personal Data for a period of time consistent with the original purpose of collection. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at privacy@walthers.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with Our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce Our agreements.
Communication Preferences
You can stop delivery of promotional e-mail or other Walthers communications by contacting Walthers at privacy@walthers.com. Additionally, when you purchase products or services from Us, We may deliver non-promotional communications related to those purchases, products or services which may not be canceled unless you cease use of the product or service.
You may at any time also opt-out of communications directly from the footer unsubscribe link in any promotional email that we send. Walthers will comply with your request within a reasonable amount of time and as soon as reasonably practical.
Changes to this Statement
We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If We make material changes to this Statement, We will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on Our home page prior to the change becoming effective. Your continued use of Walthers products, services or websites or communication with Walthers constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Statement and any updates.
Contacting Us
If you have questions or concerns, you should contact the Walthers Privacy Administrator at: privacy@walthers.com or at Our headquarters at 5601 W. Florist Ave., Milwaukee, WI 53218; 414-527-0770.
Wm. K. Walthers, Inc. Corporate Office and Store Address
5601 West Florist AvenueMilwaukee, WI 53218
Walthers Showroom Holiday Hours
Please note that our showroom will be CLOSED the following days:
Thursday and Friday, December 24th and 25th
Thursday and Friday, December 31st and January 1st
Our showroom is open BY APPOINTMENT only!
Appointment Hours: Thursday and Friday, 10am – 3pmPlease call 1-800-4-TRAINS during regular business hours to schedule an appointment and get your holiday shopping done early!!Masks are required – please bring one as we do not supply them.No mask? No problem! We will continue to take orders over the phone for curbside pickup.
Thank you for your business!
Customer Center
Contact Us
Manage Preferences
Walthers Limited Warranty
Product Resource Pages
FAQs
Shipping
Returns and Replacements
Careers
We respect your rights to privacy, if you would like to request that your information not be exchanged or sold in any manner please email us directly for removal from any internal lists.
Sign Up Today
Sign up for Walthers emails to get special offers and news!
© Copyright 2017, Wm. K. Walthers, Inc.
– All Rights Reserved. Model Railroading Supplies and More
Trademark Information | Privacy Statement | Conditions of Use
